<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Terraform on Crismar.Me</title><link>https://crmejia.github.io/tags/terraform/</link><description>Recent content in Terraform on Crismar.Me</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 21:57:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://crmejia.github.io/tags/terraform/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Rebuilding crismar.me in Terraform</title><link>https://crmejia.github.io/posts/rebuilding-crismar-me-in-terraform/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 21:57:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://crmejia.github.io/posts/rebuilding-crismar-me-in-terraform/</guid><description>Howdy. It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I&amp;rsquo;ve maintained the blog. So instead of upgrading everything manually I&amp;rsquo;ve just decided to rewrite everything in Terraform and migrate the data.
Create the new Droplet using Terraform First, we need to set up the Digital Ocean Terraform provider following this guide. I added my token as an environment variable. Afterwards, we can create the droplet itself following the digital ocean droplet resource docs. I&amp;rsquo;ve published the code on GitHub if you want to have a look.</description></item><item><title>My Hashiconf '17 Experience</title><link>https://crmejia.github.io/posts/my-hashiconf-17-experience/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 21:58:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://crmejia.github.io/posts/my-hashiconf-17-experience/</guid><description>Last week I had the opportunity to attend Hashiconf ‘17 in Austin, Texas. I loved the atmosphere at the event and the city. I met some interesting people and learned how they use Hashicorp products to solve their problems. Here is a brief summary of my favorite talks and experiences.
Front row #Hashiconf keynote pic.twitter.com/QDSWUTRBns
— Crismar Mejia (@CrismarMOz) September 19, 2017
How to Build Reusable, Composable, Battle-tested Terraform Modules by Yevgeniy Brikman The Terraform series of post I’ve talked about in my last post were written by Yevgeniy.</description></item><item><title>Creating a Simple Cluster with Terraform</title><link>https://crmejia.github.io/posts/creating-a-simple-cluster-with-terraform/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 00:41:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://crmejia.github.io/posts/creating-a-simple-cluster-with-terraform/</guid><description>Since my last post I’ve been reading about Consul. Also, I found an interesting book: Site Reliability Engineering by Google. So far I’ve read the intro and first chapter and I’m captivated. I want to take my career into SRE/DevOps and this book provides good insight. However, this post is about Terraform, I found a great blog and learned more about it.
The Case for Terraform I found a great series of posts by the engineers at Gruntwork called A Comprehensive Guide to Terraform.</description></item></channel></rss>