<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Crismar.Me</title><link>https://crmejia.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Crismar.Me</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 21:57:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://crmejia.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Rebuilding crismar.me in Terraform</title><link>https://crmejia.github.io/posts/rebuilding-crismar-me-in-terraform/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 21:57:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://crmejia.github.io/posts/rebuilding-crismar-me-in-terraform/</guid><description>Howdy. It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I&amp;rsquo;ve maintained the blog. So instead of upgrading everything manually I&amp;rsquo;ve just decided to rewrite everything in Terraform and migrate the data.
Create the new Droplet using Terraform First, we need to set up the Digital Ocean Terraform provider following this guide. I added my token as an environment variable. Afterwards, we can create the droplet itself following the digital ocean droplet resource docs. I&amp;rsquo;ve published the code on GitHub if you want to have a look.</description></item><item><title>January &amp; February '18: ReactiveOps, Career Goals, PyCaribbean</title><link>https://crmejia.github.io/posts/january-february-18-reactiveops-career-goals-pycaribbean/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 18:17:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://crmejia.github.io/posts/january-february-18-reactiveops-career-goals-pycaribbean/</guid><description>Long time no see. I’ve kept busy and also got great news. On the 5th of February, I started a job as a Site Reliability Engineer for ReactiveOps. I’m excited and grateful for this opportunity.
Today is my first day as a Site Reliability Engineer for @ReactiveOps Very excited to be working with great people on Kubernetes!
— Crismar Mejia (@CrismarMOz) February 5, 2018
Getting a job in the area was one of my career goals for this year.</description></item><item><title>My CloudNativeCon + KubeCon '17 Experience</title><link>https://crmejia.github.io/posts/my-cloudnativecon-kubecon-17-experience/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2017 18:07:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://crmejia.github.io/posts/my-cloudnativecon-kubecon-17-experience/</guid><description>I was awarded a diversity scholarship to go to CloudNativeCon + Kubecon in Austin. I was selected in the second round, only 30 scholarships were offered at first. However, thanks to the efforts of the diversity committee they were able to offer 73 more scholarships. I’m very grateful for the diligence of these ladies to extend this amazing opportunity to more people.
103 attendees here this week received diversity scholarships!</description></item><item><title>Journal: Latter Half of October '17</title><link>https://crmejia.github.io/posts/latter_half_oct17/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 16:03:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://crmejia.github.io/posts/latter_half_oct17/</guid><description>So here is an update on what I’ve been doing in the latter half of October.
Prometheus I’m finally playing around with Prometheus and monitoring which is something I wanted to do for a long time. I’ve started by creating a 5 node cluster on GKE and then following a simple guide, Kubernetes monitoring with Prometheus in 15 minutes by Giancarlo Rubio. Afterwards, I watched two talks about the subject Monitoring, the Prometheus Way by Julius Volz, one of the founders of Prometheus.</description></item><item><title>September &amp; October '17: kubeadm, K8s API, VIM, and a little Housekeeping</title><link>https://crmejia.github.io/posts/september-october-17-kubeadm-k8s-api/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 19:33:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://crmejia.github.io/posts/september-october-17-kubeadm-k8s-api/</guid><description>I’m trying a new approach for my documenting process. Namely:
Shorter posts on the blog. More tweets to share more of the day-to-day. Walkthrough guides will now be versioned(as they should) on GitHub. Without further ado here’s what I’ve been up to:
Bare Metal &amp;amp; kubeadm I picked up kubeadm and build a bare metal Kubernetes cluster. I wrote a guide about it, you can find it on GitHub.</description></item><item><title>My Hashiconf '17 Experience</title><link>https://crmejia.github.io/posts/my-hashiconf-17-experience/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 21:58:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://crmejia.github.io/posts/my-hashiconf-17-experience/</guid><description>Last week I had the opportunity to attend Hashiconf ‘17 in Austin, Texas. I loved the atmosphere at the event and the city. I met some interesting people and learned how they use Hashicorp products to solve their problems. Here is a brief summary of my favorite talks and experiences.
Front row #Hashiconf keynote pic.twitter.com/QDSWUTRBns
— Crismar Mejia (@CrismarMOz) September 19, 2017
How to Build Reusable, Composable, Battle-tested Terraform Modules by Yevgeniy Brikman The Terraform series of post I’ve talked about in my last post were written by Yevgeniy.</description></item><item><title>Creating a Simple Cluster with Terraform</title><link>https://crmejia.github.io/posts/creating-a-simple-cluster-with-terraform/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 00:41:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://crmejia.github.io/posts/creating-a-simple-cluster-with-terraform/</guid><description>Since my last post I’ve been reading about Consul. Also, I found an interesting book: Site Reliability Engineering by Google. So far I’ve read the intro and first chapter and I’m captivated. I want to take my career into SRE/DevOps and this book provides good insight. However, this post is about Terraform, I found a great blog and learned more about it.
The Case for Terraform I found a great series of posts by the engineers at Gruntwork called A Comprehensive Guide to Terraform.</description></item><item><title>Creating Infrastructure with Terraform</title><link>https://crmejia.github.io/posts/creating-infrastructure-with-terraform/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2017 20:15:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://crmejia.github.io/posts/creating-infrastructure-with-terraform/</guid><description>I’m attending HashiConf ‘17, an annual tech conference from HashiCorp. I came across HashiCorp sometime ago when I was playing around with Vagrant, a neat tool for creating and managing dev environments using virtual machines. I became aware of the conference thanks to Twitter and reached out to the organizers asking if there was any financial aid or scholarships. Lucky for me, I was offered a complimentary ticket to attend. So here I come HashiConf ‘17!</description></item><item><title>July &amp; August 2017: My first PRs</title><link>https://crmejia.github.io/posts/july-august-2017-my-first-prs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 19:45:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://crmejia.github.io/posts/july-august-2017-my-first-prs/</guid><description>So last time I mentioned I was looking to contribute to the Kubernetes project. After an initially steep learning curve, I’ve managed to get two PRs approved on Service Catalog, a Kubernetes incubator project. Here’s how that happened.
How I got started I was looking for a good place to start on the k8s project. Coincidentally, I came across a tweet by @TheNikhita and decided to reach out and ask her about her experience and tips contributing to k8s.</description></item><item><title>June 2017 Journal: What I've Been up to</title><link>https://crmejia.github.io/posts/june-2017-journal-what-ive-been-up-to/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2017 11:11:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://crmejia.github.io/posts/june-2017-journal-what-ive-been-up-to/</guid><description>Howdy folks! It’s been a while. I’ve kept myself busy this past month learning about different things in kubernetes and distributed systems. I’ve document most of it but I felt that nothing was worth a post that is until I found this article by Sam Jarman titled “Online Presence”. The article talks about, you guessed it, online presence in its various forms(blogs, vlogs, github, etc) but what really caught my attention was a linked video: Gary Vaynerchuk’s Document, Don’t Create.</description></item><item><title>AWS EC2 + Bitnami and HTTPS w/Let's Encrypt</title><link>https://crmejia.github.io/posts/aws-ec2-bitnami-and-https-wlets-encrypt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 20:07:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://crmejia.github.io/posts/aws-ec2-bitnami-and-https-wlets-encrypt/</guid><description>I ran out of credit for Google Cloud. Turns out running a cluster is quite expensive. For the sake of having a blog while I keep learning about kubernetes and other technologies I decided to go with a simpler(and cheaper) approach to blogging.
Enter AWS + Bitnami I chose to start AWS free trial and create a blog using the prepacked Bitnami solution. This deployment runs on a good ol’ VM and is cheap.</description></item><item><title>Let There be a Domain</title><link>https://crmejia.github.io/posts/let-there-be-a-domain/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 18:41:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://crmejia.github.io/posts/let-there-be-a-domain/</guid><description>Now that the blog is back up finally we can finally get around to setting up a domain. First thing we would need is a static IP to point the domain to. So let’s do.
Static IP on GKE for a Kubernetes Service I did not find an official guide on how to do this. Fortunately, I found a blog post and a Stack Overflow answer that explains how to accomplish this.</description></item><item><title>Blog Day 1. Site Unavailable!?</title><link>https://crmejia.github.io/posts/blog-day-1-site-unavailable/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 21:39:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://crmejia.github.io/posts/blog-day-1-site-unavailable/</guid><description>Tuesday, March 21, 2017 around 6:30 pm Just got home from work to find my brand new blog very slow. Which I find odd since I’m still at 104.196.107.177 and only shared the IP with a friend. So I’m jumped on the cloud shell to have a looks at the pods logs:
$kubectl logs wordpress-3772071710-cn374
10.1xx.xxx.xxx- - [21/Mar/2017:22:44:56 +0000] &amp;quot;GET http://weibo.cn/5179282824 HTTP/1.1&amp;quot; 301 332 &amp;quot;http://weibo.cn/5179282824&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Mozilla/5.0 (Windows NT 6.1; WOW64; Trident/7.</description></item><item><title>From 0 to Blogging: WordPress on Kubernetes</title><link>https://crmejia.github.io/posts/from-0-to-blogging-wordpress-on-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2017 22:50:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://crmejia.github.io/posts/from-0-to-blogging-wordpress-on-kubernetes/</guid><description>I want to become a SRE/Distributed Systems Engineer. An expert in the field suggested I started small by setting up a WordPress blog using Kubernetes + Docker on a local machine or a cloud like a droplet from Digital Ocean or GKE from Google. So this is my journey setting up a blog.
Udacity 615: Scalable Microservices with Kubernetes I was debating where to start since I wasn’t familiar with Kubernetes or Docker.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://crmejia.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://crmejia.github.io/about/</guid><description>Hi! My name is Crismar and I’m a Site Reliability Engineer. I enjoy working on distributed systems and cloud technologies. This blog started as a Hello World project with Kubernetes and evolved into a journal of my experiences as an engineer.
I’m currently working as a Cloud Consultant and Go Software Engineer. For more information checkout the Consulting section.</description></item><item><title>Consulting</title><link>https://crmejia.github.io/consulting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://crmejia.github.io/consulting/</guid><description>I offer cloud consulting services with a focus on Kubernetes. I’m also available for Go contract work. Here’s a list of things I can help you with:
Creation and configuration of Kubernetes clusters in GKE and EKS. Installation and configuration of cluster services: ingress-nginx, Monitoring, Alerting, Logging, RBAC, Authentication. Configuration of Deployments, Ingress, HPAs, and Kubernetes setup in general. Setup monitoring and logging for your clusters. Build or extend cloud infra in AWS or GKE using terraform.</description></item></channel></rss>